in this video we're going to talk about
how to identify
the relative maximum and minimum values
of the function f of x
so
here we have a maximum a relative max
it's the highest point in that region
and over here we have a relative minimum
now the location
of these values is associated with the x
values
so we have a relative max
at x equals negative three and we have a
relative min
at x equals one
now the actual relative
maximum value
is the y value that corresponds to this
point
so the y value is positive three
and here the y value is negative three
so
let's say if we were asked to find the
location of the relative maximum we
could say that it's located
at x
equals negative three
and the location
of the relative minimum
we could say it's located at
x equals 1.
and then for this part what is
the relative minimum value of f of x
so the relative minimum value
that's equal to the y value that
corresponds to that point so that's
negative three
and the relative maximum value
is the y value that corresponds to that
point
which is positive three
let's try another example
so identify
all of the relative extreme values the
minimums the maximums the location and
their actual values
so here we have a minimum
and we have a relative maximum
a minimum and another
maximum
so the first relative minimum is located
at an x value of negative four
and the second one is located at an x
value of one
the first relative maximum is located at
approximately x equals negative two
and the second relative max is at
x equals four
so that's the location of these extreme
values
now the first actual relative minimum
value
has a y value of
two
and the second minimum value
the y value is negative one
now the first maximum value on the left
it has a y value of five
and the second one
has a y value of
three
now sometimes depending on what type of
problem you're working on
the problem may ask for the entire
coordinate of each of these relative
maximums and minimums so for this one
you could say it's located at negative
four comma two
and then this maximum have the point
let's put it here negative two comma
five
and for this one it's
four three
and for this minimum it's one negative
one
so you can actually write the entire
point
if you want to
you